this problem
asks us to write a program that asks the
user for their age in years
and then converts that age to months and
outputs a message to the user
so we'll start by displaying a prompt to
the user with
put s
and our prompt displays appropriately so
we can move on to the next step
now we need our program to pause and get
some input from the user
we'll do that using get s
now we want to store the user input in a
variable so that we can use it later in
our program
and we'll give this variable a nice
descriptive name
and call it age in years
[Music]
and for now let's just
display the agent years back to the user
after they input it
so the program prompts us for our age
and i'll input 35
[Music]
the next step of our problem is to
convert that age in years
into age and months
and we can do that by multiplying the
age in years by 12.
let's initialize a local variable age in
months
and we can set it equal to 12
times the age in years
let's see what happens when we run our
program now
[Music]
you can see that an exception has been
raised
this is a type error and it's because we
try to
multiply a string by an integer
[Music]
what's interesting about this here is
that if we put the string
on the left side of the operator
and output the result
you'll see that age in months is
actually the string 35
12 times
so neither one of these possibilities is
what we want
[Music]
our original type error was caused
because
user input always comes in in a string
and what we needed to do was multiply 12
by the integer representation of our age
in years
so to solve that problem we can call the
string2i method
on the user input so now let's run our
program
and see if the multiplication is being
performed appropriately
and finally it is
so now that we have the correct product
being assigned to
our age and months local variable all we
need
to do is output the age in months as
part of a display message to the user
[Music]
we can do that with string interpolation
age and months is now an integer but
when we place it within the curly braces
while performing string interpolation
ruby calls 2s on that value and converts
it back into a string
so we're able to use string
interpolation pretty seamlessly here
let's run our code
[Music]
now we're seeing the expected behavior
from our program
[Music]
we called 2i on our agent years on line
which is fine but if we were going to
continually use this value in our
program as an integer
and maybe perform more arithmetic
operations with it
we may want to just call 2i on that
input when we store it in the agent
years variable
then we can use it throughout our code
as an integer
and not have to repeatedly call 2i on
that variable
in this case our program is very small
and
it's okay to call 2i on line 3.